Morteza Montahaee Resume

▶ Status: Student at the FH Aachen (AOS), B.Sc. in Mathematics at the PNU

Skills: Java (awt, exception, io, nio, util, swing), C#/.Net(protobuf (OVF), Numerics, Threading, Collections), C++, Python (collections, csv, cv2, io, Json, math, matplotlib, multiprocessing, networkx, numpy, os, random, scipy,

shutil, seaborn(-image), skimage, sklearn, tensorflow, xml.etree, zipfile), HTML, Liquid, JavaScript (Node (bootstrap, express, jquery, mustache, Sequelize)), SHACL PHP SOL (MariaDB MYSOL), IATEX (BibTeX geometry, TibZ), Vim

SHACL, PHP, SQL (MariaDB, MYSQL), LATEX (BibTeX, geometry, TikZ), Vim

German: Advanced
 Englisch: Upper Intermediate

▶ Interest: Variationsrechnung, Differenzialgeometrie, Data Science, Design Patterns

▶ Hobbys: Wrestling, Football, Hiking, History, Mathematics

• Persian: Native language



Profil

Languages

Graduate in Applied Mathematics with completed MATSE-Apprenticeship and advanced studies in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science. Practical experience in software development with a focus on differential geometry, database management, and data science. Proven ability to work independently and collaborate effectively in a team. Deep interest in applying mathematical methods to solve complex and real-world problems, as well as researching and describing mathematical models and their implementation possibly according to design pattern solutions.

Experience

10/2019 - 08/2023 **MATSE (Apprenticeship)**

DAP RWTH

▶ Worked on the development of an NX CAD library for generating Lattice in C# using Protobuf serialization

Arabic: Elementary

- Designed workflow management of additive processes in a UML-compliant process modeling (IDAM) with Enterprise Architect (EA)
- ▶ Participated in the development of research data models in Python on the Coscine platform
- ▶ Supported MAT.TRAFFIC GmbH as part of a MATSE project work in Python: Geo-detection of intersections for intelligent traffic systems and city planning using metadata from OpenStreetMap(OSM)

08/2009 - 09/2019 Additional professional activities

NAJA, Frankenberg, Dachser, Event Probat, UB-RWTH

Verkaufsassistent (Basar) (06/2003 - 09/2005)
Wehrdienst (08/2009 - 04/2011)

▶ Aushelfer (07/2012 - 10/2014) **▶** Zusteller (11/2014 - 06/2015)

Kellner und Eventassistent (11/2014 - 10/2019)
 Aushelfer im Büchermagazin (07/2016 - 09/2016)

Education

10/2005 - 07/2009 Bachelor's Degree, in Applied Mathematics (Note: 2.2)

PNU

- ▶ Bachelor's thesis: Application of Nonlinear Conjugate Gradient Algorithms for Estimation of Electromagnetic Inversion
- ▶ Focus: Linear Algebra, Numerical (ODE) and Mathematical Analysis, Mathematical Statistics, Graph Theory, Mathematical Models of Nature (ODE)

06/2011 - 10/2016

Language Acquisition and Studies

RWTH

- German language acquisition at the Language Center of RWTH (06/2011 07/2012)
- ▶ Unfinished Mathematics M.S.c at RWTH (10/2012 10/2016): Participation in modules in Image Processing, Neuroscience, Numerics (PDE), Optimization Theory, Calculus of Variations

10/2019 - present

Studies, Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

FH-Aachen

- ▶ Focus: Linear Algebra, Stochastics, Numerics, Programming (OOP), Algorithms and Data Structures, Data Science, Databases, Software Engineering, Web and Communication Systems
- Bachelor's thesis: Application of Johnson-Lindenstrauss Lemma in Data Compression
- Anticipated graduation: 05/2024